- 圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas.
《蝙蝠侠归来》
(高谭市 33年后)
见到企鹅了!是人还是谜?
Penguin sighting! Man or myth?
他是什么? 今天专题... 又见到企鹅了
What is he? Today's edition. Another penguin sighting.
又见到企鹅了!先睹为快!
Another penguin sighting! Check it out!
怪异企鹅人住在高谭下水道中! 快来看最新目击报导!
Penguin man living in Gotham's sewers! Read all about the latest sighting!
请注意 高谭市
May I have your attention Gotham City?
今晚点燃圣诞树的时刻已经到了
It is time for tonight's lighting of the tree.
好看吧?
How about that?
半人半企鹅!十分恐怖!
Part man part penguin! All horrifying!
来喔!只要50分钱便能得知真相!
Find out for only 50 cents! Come on!
快看看存在于我们脚下的可能危险! 快来看 各位!
Read about the possible terror beneath our feet! Check it out!
快来看今天的报导! 看看最新的企鹅怪物目击报导
Read about it!
喂 这是人与鸟间的缺失环节
Missing link between man and bird.
孩子
My dear boy
有时看那种垃圾是种消遣
sometimes it's a diversion to read such rubbish.
但多数时候是浪费时间
Usually it's a waste of time.
随你说 今日专题! "企鹅:是人还是谜?"
Whatever. Today's issue! "The Penguin: Man or myth?"
环球报! 在此! 25分钱!
The Globe! Right here! 25 cents!
唔 这里是有希望的
Well here's hoping.
带点幸运的话 高谭市可以在几年后过第一个圣诞节
With luck Gotham will have its first merry Christmas in years.
我觉得很粗俗 在圣诞季节
I feel almost vulgar at Yuletide
提起新发电厂
mentioning the new power plant.
但我们若要动工兴建 就需要许可
But if we're to break ground when we must I'll need permits
法规变通 减税鼓励 那类讨厌的枝微末节
variances tax incentives. That sort of pesky nonsense.
发电厂?
Power plant?
麦斯 所有研究均显示 我们的电力足以应付到下世纪中期
Studies show we've enough power to get us into the middle of the next century.
你的分析家指的是每年1%的人口成长
Your analysts foresee growth at 1 % per annum.
那不是成长 是温和膨胀
That's a mild swelling.
试想像
Imagine
一个高谭市
a Gotham City
在未来 灯光燃起如一片繁星
of the future lit up like a blanket of stars
但却闪灭不定
but blinking on and off
电力低得令人难堪
embarrassingly low on juice.
老实说
Frankly
我因而畏缩 市长先生
I cringe Mr. Mayor.
抱歉 你的任何计划都得循正常管道
Sorry any plans must go to the usual committees
向负责委员会申请
through the usual channels.
我有个建议
I have a suggestion.
好的
Well
事实上 更像是个问题
actually really just more like a question.
恐怕我们未适当训练凯尔小姐
I'm afraid we haven't properly housebroken Ms. Kyle.
但她有个优点
In the plus column though
她泡的咖啡非常香
she makes great coffee.
爸
Dad.
市长先生 该下去为大众带来喜悦了
Mr. Mayor. Time to go down and bring joy to the masses.
"事实上 更是个问题"
"Actually more of a question."
你是愚蠢的笨狗
You stupid corn dog.
笨狗 笨狗
Corn dog corn dog.
我光靠许瑞克的员工 便可以取得重选的签名
I have enough signatures from Shreck employees to warrant a recall.
那不是威胁 只是单纯的数据
That's not a threat just simple numbers.
也许 但你没有立场 也没有候选人
Maybe. But you sure as hell don't have an issue or a candidate.
非常感谢各位女士 先生
Thank you ladies and gentlemen.
祝我们市政府的人和你们所有的人
From those of us at City Hall to each and every one of you
假期快乐
happy holidays.
今晚有位不需要多作介绍的人 与我们同在 他对本市贡献良多
We have with us a man who needs no introduction he's given us so much.
请欢迎高谭市的圣诞老人... 麦斯.许瑞克
Please welcome Gotham's own Santa Claus Max Shreck.
到人事处拿那些合约
Pick up those contracts for Personnel and
再去拿干洗衣物和纸巾
pick up the dry cleaning and paper towels .
糟糕!
Darn!
我忘了我的演讲稿
I forgot my speech.
提醒我教训那个叫什么的
Remind me to take it out on what's-her-name.
圣诞老人?
Santa Claus?
恐怕不是
Afraid not.
我只是个低贱的走运笨蛋
I'm just a poor schmo. Got lucky.
我要回馈你们
Sue me
若不满意 就告我吧
if I want to give some back.
但愿我能送出的 不只是
I only wish I could hand out more than just
昂贵的玩具
expensive baubles.
但愿我能送出世界和平
I wish I could hand out world peace
和无条件的爱
and unconditional love
包在大蝴蝶结礼盒中
wrapped in a big bow.
但是你可以
Oh but you can.
你会的
Oh but you will.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
好主意
Great idea.
不是我的主意
Not mine.
你在等什么?发出讯号!
What are you waiting for? The signal!
我们要大角色! 主导一切的那个家伙!
We want the big guy! The guy who runs the show!
你要什么?
What do you want?
不是你!
Not you!
许瑞克!
Shreck!
你得先过我这一关
You'll have to go through me.
奇普 爸 快走!救你自己!
Dad go! Save yourself!
爸 快走!
Dad go!
闭嘴!
Shut up!
蝙蝠人先生 你要是再上前一步 我就...
Take one step closer Mr. Manbat and I'll...
没打中
You missed.
哇!是蝙蝠侠
The Batman.
或只是"蝙蝠人"?
Or is it just "Batman"?
当然 任你选择
Your choice of course.
这真是
Well that was
非常短暂
very brief.
就和我生命中的所有男人一样
Just like all the men in my life.
什么男人?
What men?
但是
Well
话说回来 还有你 不过你需要治疗
then again there's you. But you need therapy.
谢谢你拯救我们 蝙蝠侠 恐怕马戏团帮又回来了
Thanks for saving the day Batman. The Circus Gang is back.
静观其后吧
We'll see.
他们差点抓走麦斯.许瑞克
They almost made off with our mover and shaker Max Shreck.
那令人难以忍受的混蛋呢?
Where is that insufferable son of a bitch?
相信你搜寻的字眼是 啊...
I believe the word you're looking for is .
事实上 这一切只是个恶梦
Actually this is all just a bad dream.
你在家中床上
You're at home in bed
无比宁静 安适地休息着
heavily sedated resting comfortably
口吐致癌物而垂将等死
dying from the carcinogens you've personally spewed
只因你毕生牟取暴利
in a lifetime of profiteering.
是悲剧性的讽刺
Tragic irony
或诗歌般的正义?
or poetic justice?
你告诉我
You tell me.
天啊 是真的
My God it's true.
下水道的企鹅人
Penguin Man of the sewer.
奇怪的是 麦斯
Odd as it may seem Max
你和我有些共通之处
you and I have something in common:
我们都被视同怪物一般
We're both perceived as monsters.
然而
But somehow
你是个倍受尊敬的怪物
you're a well-respected monster
而我则
and I am to date
不然!
not!
老实说 我不以为然 我是个生意人
Frankly I feel that's a bum rap. I'm a businessman.
强硬 对
Tough yes.
刻薄 也行 但还不足使我成为怪物
Shrewd okay. But that does not make me a monster.
别糗自己了 麦斯!
Don't embarrass yourself Max!
我对你一清二楚
I know all about you.
你隐藏 我发掘
What you hide I discover.
你弃于马桶中的
What you put in your toilet
我将它保存起来 明白吗?
I place on my mantle. Get the picture?
那是什么? 打算对我催眠吗?
Is that supposed to hypnotize me?
不 只是要让你头痛欲裂
No just give you a splitting headache.
没有效
It's not working.
喔 大男孩!
Oh you big baby!
只是空炮弹
Just blanks.
今晚我大费周章 只为杀你吗?
Would I go through all this trouble just to kill you?
不 麦斯
No Max.
我有个全然不同的目的
I have an entirely other purpose.
我准备好了 麦斯
I'm ready Max.
我已在下面太久
I've been down here too long.
我该上升了
It's time for me to ascend
重新出现
to re-emerge
借着你的帮助
with your help
你的深谙此道
your know-how
你的机伶
your savvy.
我并非生于下水道
I wasn't born in the sewer you know.
我来自
I come from
和你一样
like you.
而且和你一样 我要受到尊重!
And like you I want some respect!
得到我的基本人权
A recognition of my basic humanity.
但最重要的
But most of all
我要藉找到我父母
I want to find out who I am
来查出我是谁
by finding my parents
得知我的姓名
Iearning my human name.
高谭人视为当然的简单事情!
Simple stuff that the good people of Gotham take for granted!
那
And
我到底为何要帮你?
exactly why am I going to help you?
好的
Well .
我们开始吧
Let's start.
让我看看这里有些什么
Let's see what we have in here.
一些有毒的废水
A batch of toxic waste
取自你干净的纺织厂!
from your clean textile plant!
这种废物 后面有一大池!
There's a whole lagoon of this crud in the back!
那可能来自任何地方
It could have come from anywhere.
证明你拥有高谭市 半数易燃建筑的文件呢?
What about the documents that prove you own half of the firetraps in Gotham City?
若有那种文件
If there were such documents
而且我不允许有
that's not an admission
它们早就被切碎了
they would've been shredded.
好主意
Good idea.
许多胶带和一点耐心 情况便截然不同
A lot of tape and a little patience make all the difference.
对了
By the way
你的老合伙人... 佛列德.亚特金好吗?
how's Fred Atkins your old partner?
佛列德?
Fred?
事实上 佛列德他
Fred's actually .
我相信他正在度延长假期 他很好
I believe he's on an extended vacation. He's good.
很好
Good.
你好 麦斯 记得我吗? 我是佛列德的手!
Hiya Max. Remember me? I'm Fred's hand!
要向其它部份的肢体致意吗?
Want to greet any other body parts?
记住 麦斯
Remember Max
你摒弃的 我珍惜
you flush it I flaunt it.
你知道吗 企鹅先生?
You know what Mr. Penguin sir?
我想 或许
I think perhaps
我能协助你策划一个欢迎返乡的策略
I could help orchestrate a "Welcome Home" scenario for you.
等我们俩都回到家 或许我们能互相帮助
Once we're both back home perhaps we could help each other.
你不会后悔的 许瑞克先生
You won't regret this Mr. Shreck.
亲爱的 我回来了!
Honey I'm home!
噢 我忘了 我未婚
Oh I forgot. I'm not married.
猫咪小姐
Miss Kitty.
从妳拒绝分享的性胡闹活动归来了吗?
Back from more sexual escapades you refuse to share?
不是我爱刺探
Not that I'd ever pry.
喝妳的晚餐吧
Drink your dinner.
怎么了?
What?
怎么会有人如此可悲?
How can anyone be so pathetic?
对 对妳而言 我是可悲 但我是个上班女郎
Yes to you I seem pathetic but I'm a working girl.
得付房租 妳若能贡献点生活费 而不要开溜就好了
Must pay the rent. Maybe if you chipped in instead of stepping out.
瑟琳娜 亲爱的 是妈 只是打电话问候妳一下
Selina dear it's your mother. Just calling to say hello.
对 但是
Yeah but .
但是我很失望 妳不回家过圣诞节
But I'm disappointed you're not coming home for Christmas.
我要和妳讨论 为何妳坚持要在高谭市受折磨
I want to discuss why you insist on languishing in Gotham City
像一些低级秘书一样
as some lowly secretary.
是低级助理
Lowly assistant.
瑟琳娜 记得我们的圣诞出游计划吗?
Selina about that Christmas getaway we planned .
我将要独自去 萧博士说我需要独处 而非附属品
I'll be going alone. Dr. Shaw says I need to be my own person not an appendage.
真是个附属品!
Some appendage!
瑟琳娜.凯尔的录音机盛宴永不停息
The party never stops on Selina Kyle's answering machine.
看来上次打板球时 我该让他赢的
I should've let him win that last racquetball game.
哈啰
Hello
瑟琳娜.凯尔
Selina Kyle.
我们要告诉妳有种新的高谭女士香水
We're calling to tell you about exciting new Gotham Lady perfume.
它会使女人感觉像女人 而且男人不会有抱怨
It makes women feel like women and the men have no complaints either.
嗨 瑟琳娜 这是提醒妳自己　真蠢! 妳得回办公室去
This is yourself reminding you to come all the way back to the office
如果妳忘记带布鲁斯.韦恩的档案回来
if you forgot the Bruce Wayne file .
你这个笨蛋!　 星期三有个会议
You stupid corn dog!
加班吗?
Working late?
我只是在帮你预备明早 和布鲁斯.韦恩开会的资料
I'm just boning up for your Bruce Wayne meeting in the morning.
我调出发电厂企划案的所有档案
I pulled all the files on the proposed power plant
还有预备请韦恩先生投资的文件 我甚至打开了保护档...
and Mr. Wayne's hoped-for investment. I even opened the protected files...
多勤奋啊!
How industrious!
妳是如何打开保护档的?
How did you open the protected files?
我能问吗?
May I ask?
我想你的密码是"Geraldo" 是你吉娃娃的名字
I figured your password was "Geraldo " your Chihuahua and it was.
这实在非常有趣 虽然在技术上有一点难懂
This is all very interesting though a bit on the technical side
我是指发电厂 如何只在名义上是发电厂
about how the power plant is a power plant in name only
而事实上 它将是个大的
since in fact it's going to be a big giant
巨大的 容电器
big giant capacitor.
它不会产生电力 反而会吸收
And instead of generating power it'll be sucking power from
高谭市的电力
Gotham City
并且贮存起来
and storing it
囤积它
stockpiling it
我得说那是个非常新奇的方式
which is a very novel approach I'd say.
妳有将此事告诉谁?
Who'd you say this to?
没告诉别人
Nobody.
好奇会使猫如何呢?
What did curiosity do to the cat?
我不是猫
I'm no cat.
我只是个助理
I'm just an assistant.
是个秘书
A secretary.
而且是非常好的一个
And a very good one.
太好了?
Too good?
听着
Listen
那是我们的秘密 真的
it's our secret. Honest.
你怎能对一个无意义的人如此残忍?
How can you be so mean to someone so meaningless?
这发电厂
This power plant
将是我的传家宝 是我遗留下来的
is my legacy. It's what I leave behind.
留给奇普
For Chip.
任何事都无法阻止
Nothing must prevent that.
好 动手吧 恐吓我 欺压我 若能使你觉得强大
Go ahead. Intimidate me. Bully me if it makes you feel big.
反正你又不可能杀了我!
It's not like you can kill me!
事实上 很有可能
Actually it's a lot like that.
有那么一会 你真的吓到我了
For a second you really frightened me.
真是的
Really?
亲爱的 我回来了!
Honey I'm home!
噢 我忘了 我未婚
Oh I forgot. I'm not married.
瑟琳娜 我是妈 打电话给我
Selina this is your mother. Call me.
瑟琳娜 我是妈 妳为何没回我电话?
Selina this is your mother. Why haven't you called me back?
哈啰 瑟琳娜.凯尔
Hello Selina Kyle.
我们打电话 是想确定妳已试用过高谭女士香水
We're just calling to make sure you've tried Gotham Lady perfume.
在办公室只要喷一下 你老板会要妳下班后留下
One whiff of this and your boss will ask you to stay after work
开二人烛光员工会议
for a candlelight staff meeting for two.
高谭女士香水 许瑞克百货公司仅售
Gotham Lady perfume. Exclusively at Shreck's department store.
我不知道妳觉得如何 猫咪小姐 但我觉得
I don't know about you Miss Kitty but I feel
真是棒透了
so much yummier.
女士 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen:
我再度在你们面前 谴责与我们共存于这城市的紊乱
I stand before you again to denounce the urban chaos we live with in our city.
它得停止
It's got to stop.
它将停止! 在这应该聚合的时节
It's going to stop! Our community is coming apart
我们的社区正崩离
in a season when it should be coming together.
我不在乎批评者会怎么说 现在是圣诞时节
I don't care what the cynics may say. This is the Christmas season
应该是愈合的时候
and should be a healing time.
我不只以官员的身份声明
I say that not only as an official
更以丈夫与父亲的立场说
but as a husband and a father.
昨晚的暴行不会再发生
Last night's violence won't happen again.
我不擅于言词 因此我只能说"谢了"
I'm not good at speeches so I'll just say "Thanks".
天啊 是可怕的企鹅人
It's the hideous Penguin Man.
孩子你带走 但请别伤害我!
Take the baby. Just don't hurt me please!
这是数分钟前在高谭广场 发生的非凡情况
This was the remarkable scene only minutes ago in Gotham Plaza.
神秘的企鹅解救市长之子
The mysterious Penguin saving the life of the mayor's baby
- 并宣布他的存在 - 我要的回报
- and announcing his presence. - All I want in return
是想找回
is a chance
找出我的父母
to find my mom and dad.
一个查出他们是谁
A chance to find out who they are
进而知道
and thusly
我是谁的机会
who I am.
然后
And then
从我父母那儿
with my parents
设法了解 为什么
try to understand why.
为何他们做出他们觉得非做不可的事
Why they did what I guess they felt they had to do
对一个孩子
to a child
一个生来
who was born
有点不同的
a little different.
孩子
A child
让他度过第一个圣诞节
who spent his first Christmas
和之后许多个
and many since
都在下水道中
in a sewer.
韦恩先生?有何不对吗? 没有
Mr. Wayne? Something wrong?
他的父母
His parents.
再度说明 本画面直接拍自高谭广场
This scene direct from Gotham Plaza.
但愿他找到他们
I hope he finds them.
他正站在高谭市模范市民... 麦斯.许瑞克的旁边
Here he is standing alongside Gotham's leading citizen Max Shreck.
说句话好吗? 市民们想知道
How about a statement? People want to know.
- 企鹅人不该被打扰的! - 这是公共场所!
- Penguin's not to be disturbed! - It's a public place!
- 走开 现在 快走开 - 新闻舆论的自由!
- Walk. Now. Move. - Freedom of the press!
等一下
Wait a minute.
是什么样的想法 让你想寻找你的根
What about the freedom to rediscover your roots
掺杂尊严和隐私?
with dignity and privacy?
企鹅是你私人的朋友?
Is the Penguin a personal friend?
他是整个城市的私人朋友 只要有着一颗心
He's a personal friend of the whole city so have a heart.
让法规休息一下 这是圣诞节
Give the Constitution a rest. It's Christmas.
"红三角马戏团表演声势浩大 还有凶猛的狮子"
"Red Triangle Circus put on a swell show with fierce lions.
"马戏团表演将为期两周 "
"Circus returns for a two-week .
"小孩会喜欢的 ."
"Kids will love ."
谢谢
Thanks.
好冷!
It's cold!
这是掺有马铃薯的奶油汤
It's vichyssoise.
冷了才好喝
It's supposed to be cold.
"马戏团回来 又带着怪异的表演 并不适合小孩 "
"Circus is back with a freak show may not be suitable for kids
" 特写一位狮子头女士 "
" featuring a poodle lady
" 世界最胖的人 "
" the world's fattest man
" 水上鸟男孩"
" and Aquatic Bird Boy."
你为何决心证明
Why are you determined to prove
这个企鹅人所言不实?
that this Penguin is not what he seems?
你一定得当全城唯一的"人兽"吗?
Must you be the only lonely "man-beast" in town?
"马戏团昨天收起帐篷 "
"The circus folded its tents yesterday
" 在数个城镇发生无数儿童失踪案件后"
" after reports of missing children in several towns.
"警方已关闭红三角表演场"
"Police have closed down the Red Triangle fairgrounds.
"然而 至少有一名畸型表演者 "
"However at least one freak-show performer vanished before
" 在接受侦讯前失踪了"
" he could be questioned."
我想你觉得好多了 主人
I suppose you feel better now.
没有
No.
事实上 我觉得更糟
Actually I feel worse.
你为何还在外面?
Why're you still out?
你是在关心那个英雄般怪异的企鹅人吗?
Are you concerned about that strange heroic Penguin person?
我想他知道他父母是谁
I think he knows who his parents are.
他另有所图
There's something else.
企鹅先生
Mr. Penguin .
企鹅是鸟类却不会飞!
A penguin is a bird that cannot fly!
我是个人!
I am a man!
我有名字!
I have a name!
奥兹瓦.卡伯波特!
Oswald Cobblepot!
你从未和他们生活在一起?
You'll never be able to settle with them?
是的
True.
我是他们"第一流"的儿子
I was their "Number-One"" son
而他们待我却像二流的
and they treated me like number two.
但人类的天性是害怕
But it's human nature to fear
奇特的
the unusual.
或许
Perhaps
当我拿着
when I held my
小孩玩的拨浪鼓
Tiffany baby rattle
以带有光泽的蹼状手
with a shiny flipper
而非五只圆胖的手指
instead of five chubby digits
他们吓到了
they freaked.
但我原谅他们
But I forgive them.
"企鹅人原谅父母了!" "我对自己与世界都感到平和!"
"Penguin forgives parents!", "I'm at peace with myself and the world!"
"只要有心 便不需要手"
"Don't need hands as long as you got heart."
"我的心充满爱 我觉得有五呎高"
"My heart is filled with love. I feel five feet tall."
- 他像只变成王子的青蛙 - 不 他更像只企鹅
- He's like a frog that became a prince. - No he's more like a penguin.
好了 漂亮的小姑娘
Now now pretty little thing.
乖乖听话
Nice and easy.
我喜欢高大强壮 而且 勇于展现力量对付体型小他一半的人
I love a big strong man who's not afraid to show it with someone half his size.
温柔点 这是我的第一次
Be gentle it's my first time.
踢-踏-拳
Tic-tac-toe.
谢谢 我 妳使自己容易受害 是吗?
You make it easy don't you?
总是等着蝙蝠侠来救妳
Always waiting for some Batman to save you.
我是猫女
I am Catwoman
听我怒吼
hear me roar.
我想请你喝咖啡 但我的助理正在休假
I'd offer you coffee but my assistant is using her vacation time.
好时机 反正过年之前 除了盗贼以外 大家都想放松点
Good time. Everyone but the bandits'll be slacking off till after the New Year.
我不确定是否喜欢你的推论 布鲁斯
I'm not sure I like the inference.
抱歉 麦斯 我不觉得我有做推论
I didn't realize I made one.
我现在促销发电厂计划 因为将来花费会更高
I'm pushing this power plant now because it'll cost more later.
省一百万等于赚一百万
A million saved is a million earned.
我做了一份报告 也许你想看看
I commissioned this report. Take a look at it.
麦斯 重点是高谭市已供电过量 我确信你知道
Gotham City has a power surplus. I'm sure you know that.
我的问题是
My question is:
你的目的为何?
What's your angle?
"供电过量?" 布鲁斯 你该惭愧!
"Power surplus?" Bruce shame on you!
没那回事 电力再多都不为过
No such thing. One can never have too much power.
我的生命若有何意义 那就是意义
If my life has a meaning that's the meaning.
我将与你唱反调 我已和市长谈过 我们看法一致
I'll fight you. I've already spoken to the mayor and we agree.
市长多如过江之鲫
Mayors come and go.
贵族容易没落
Blue bloods tire easily.
你以为能和拳王许瑞克打上15回合吗?
Can you go 15 rounds with Muhammad Shreck?
看来得拭目以待
I guess we'll find out.
当然 我没有卡伯波特 那种犯罪集团首领的支持
Of course I don't have a crime boss like Cobblepot in my corner.
"犯罪集团首领?" 证明你知道什么
"Crime boss?" Shows what you know
"天之骄子先生"
"Mr. To-The-Manor-Born-With-A-Silver-Spoon."
奥兹瓦是高谭市的新英雄
Oswald is Gotham's new golden boy.
他父母若未嫌弃他 你们俩或许会是同学室友
If his parents hadn't 86'ed him you'd have been bunkies at prep school.
奥兹瓦控制红三角帮 我还无法证明 但我们俩...
He controls the Red Triangle Gang. I can't prove it yet but we both...
韦恩 我不允许办公室内有揭人隐私之举
I'll not stand for mud-slinging here.
我的助理若在此 早已护送你出去...
If my assistant was here she'd have already escorted you out...
到任何他想去的地方
Anywhere he wants.
可能是夜总会 洞穴
Preferably some nightspot grotto
或者
or
隐密的藏身处
secluded hideaway.
好西装 谢谢
Nice suit.
瑟琳娜 瑟琳娜
Selina. Selina.
那是我的名字 百万麦斯 别念太多 否则我要你买个新的赔我
That's my name don't wear it out or I'll make you buy me a new one.
瑟琳娜 这是布鲁斯
This is Bruce
韦恩
Wayne.
是 我们见过
We've met.
有吗?
Have we?
噢 抱歉 我误以为自己是别人
No I'm sorry. I mistook me for somebody else.
你意思是... "误认我"
You mean "mistook me."
我误以为我 对 我不是那么说的吗?
Isn't that what I said?
不 我想不是
I don't think so.
怎么回事?
What happened?
妳在滑雪坡上受伤了吗?
Did you hurt yourself on that ski slope?
因此妳才缩短假期回来?
Is that why you cut short your vacation? Came back?
很模糊
It's a blur.
我是说 未完全失去记忆
Not complete amnesia.
我记得玛丽.玛格丽特修女在教堂呕吐
I remember Sister Mary Margaret puking in church
而贝西.莱利说那是害喜
and Betsy saying it was morning sickness.
我也记得有次上学 忘了穿内裤
And the time I forgot to wear my underpants to school
而注意到的男孩 名叫瑞奇.佛莱伯格
and the name of the boy who noticed was Ricky Friedburg.
他已经死了
He's dead now.
但昨晚
But last night
完全模糊
complete blur.
很不可思议吧?
Couldn't you just die?
瑟琳娜 拜托妳
Please
送韦恩先生出去
show out Mr. Wayne.
乐意之至
With pleasure.
你的外套 韦恩先生
Your coat Mr. Wayne.
你不像是那种和许瑞克做生意的人
You don't seem like the type who does business with Shreck.
不 你不像是那种会听命于他的人
No. You don't seem like the type to take orders from him.
嗯 那真是
Well that's a
说来话长
Iong story.
我可以腾出点时间
I could free up some time.
- 我记下了 - 我很想听
- I'm listed. - I'm tempted.
我要工作
I'm working.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
爸 你相信她说的话吗?
You buy that blurry business?
女人
Women.
任何事我都不讶异 奇普
Nothing surprises me
除了你过世的母亲
except your late mother.
谁会想到瑟琳娜竟有堪受毁坏的脑袋?
Who'd have thought Selina had a brain to damage?
最坏结果吗?
Bottom line?
她企图勒索我 我将她推出更高的窗
She tries to blackmail me I'll drop her out of a higher window.
此时
Meantime
我有更重要的事
I've got badder fish to fry.
奥兹瓦
Oswald
我是麦斯
it's Max.
你在家吗?
You're home?
你好吗?
How've you been?
你众多的家人?
Your extended family?
有家庭真好
Good to have a family.
我现在宁可不受打扰
I'd rather not be disturbed now.
下楼 奥兹瓦 我要给你一个惊喜
Come on downstairs Oswald. I have a surprise.
我不喜欢惊喜
I don't like surprises.
下来吧
Come on.
别偷看
Don't peek.
你会破坏惊喜的
You'll spoil it.
是的 奉受是个重担 我很清楚
Adulation is a cross to bear. God knows I know.
但在进步的道路上 有人必须被取代的 市长
But someone's got to supplant our standing in the way of progress Mayor.
别否认 卡伯波特先生 你有那种魔力
And don't deny it Mr. Cobblepot you've got the magic.
你的非凡魅力远胜过我们 下来吧
Your charisma's bigger than both of us. Come on down.
市长?
Mayor?
市长
Mayor.
麦斯 十一月才选举 现在是十二月底耶
Elections happen in November. It's late December.
不用担心
Don't worry.
我要你见见珍和乔希... 我的形象顾问
I want you to meet Jen and Josh my image consultants.
来
Here.
拾回你天生的权利
Reclaim your birthright.
我是珍 嗨
I'm Jen.
好 我看看 首先我要做的是 将这些小手套戴在你手上
Okay let's see. What I'd like to do first is put these gloves on you.
我们的研究显示 我们的选民喜欢手指
Our research tells us that voters like fingers.
因此 若将它藏起来 我们
So if we were to just lose this .
我们改天再戴好了
We'll do it another time.
下水道没多少能反光的平面 对吧?
Not a lot of reflective surfaces in the sewer huh?
不过 有可能更糟
Still it could be worse.
我的鼻子可能血流不止
My nose could be gushing blood.
你的鼻子可能 你的意思是说 ?
What do you mean by that?
所有人回去工作!
Everybody back to work!
让我们造就
Let's make
一位市长!
a mayor!
你说得对 我们错过正常排定的选举
You're right we missed the regular election
但当选官员可以改选 弹劾
but elected officials can be recalled impeached
罢黜.像尼克松 艾格纽
given the boot. Look at Nixon Agnew.
再想想你
Then think of you
奥兹瓦.卡伯波特填补其位
Oswald Cobblepot filling the void.
我倒想填补她
I'd like to fill her void.
我们需要签名 以促成改选 那些我能供应 奥兹瓦
We'll need signatures to overturn the ballot. I can supply those.
- 教她我的法国鳍把戏 - 奥兹瓦 我们还需要一样东西
- Teach her my French flipper trick. - We need one more thing.
一块踏板吗?
A platform?
停止环球温室效应 开始环球冷却效应 使世界成为巨大的冰箱
Stop global warming. Start global cooling. Make the world an icebox.
我喜欢 但要改选市长 需要一个触媒 导火线
I like it. But to get the mayor recalled we must have a catalyst.
"你做得很好 卡伯波特市长"
"You're doing great Mayor Cobblepot."
"你的餐桌准备好了 卡伯波特市长"
"Your table is ready Mayor Cobblepot."
"我需要你 奥兹瓦 我现在就需要你!"
"l need you Oswald. I need you now! "
"那是我见过最大的伞"
"That's the biggest parasol I've ever seen."
很快就会发生东京湾意外 或雷斯塔格大火
Soon an incident like the Gulf of Tonkin or the Reichstag fire .
你要我在上面的老朋友
You want my old friends up there
使市长发狂吗?
to drive the mayor into a foaming frenzy?
- 正是 - 听来很好玩
- Exactly. - Sounds fun.
但是
But
我不能分神 麦斯
I mustn't get sidetracked Maxie.
我有我的正事要办
I have my own things to tend to.
"想转移话题吗?" 奥兹瓦 打从你父母草率抛弃你到现在
"Sidetracked?" This is your chance to fulfill your destiny
这是你达成天命的机会
that your parents carelessly discarded.
你是指重拾我天生的权利?
Reclaim my birthright you mean?
试想身为市长后 你将得到媒体的注意
Imagine as mayor you have the ear of the media
企业大亨将尊重你的意见
access to the captains of industry
无限制的嬉闹
unlimited poontang.
你的条件很诱人 麦斯
You drive a hard bargain Maxie.
好吧 我就当市长
All right I'll be mayor.
烧吧 宝贝 烧吧!
Burn baby burn!
- 她是谁? - 她是什么?
- Who is she? - What is she?
我不知道是要开火 还是坠入爱河
I don't know whether to open fire or fall in love.
可怜的家伙
You poor guys.
手枪和私处老是搞不清楚
Always confusing your pistols with your privates.
别伤害我们 小姐 我们的薪水不到三百块
Don't hurt us. Our take-home's less than $300.
薪水太高了 滚吧
You're overpaid. Hit the road.
尽管打我吧
Go ahead and hit me.
欣赏你的作品吗?
Admiring your handiwork?
参观暴乱的场面
Touring the riot scene.
沉重地评估破坏情况
Gravely assessing the devastation.
尽"荣耀市长"的职责
"Upstanding-Mayor" stuff.
你不是市长
You're not the mayor.
世事多变
Things change.
你有何企图?
What do you want?
多直接的方法啊
The direct approach.
我欣赏一个戴面具的人能如此
I admire that in a man with a mask.
你不会真的以为你会赢吧?
You don't really think you'll win do you?
世事多变
Things change.
我先看到她的 得走了
I saw her first. Got to fly.
你怎能如此?我是个女人!
How could you? I'm a woman!
对不起 我
I'm sorry.
如我所说 我是个女人 不能让人视为理所当然
As I was saying I'm a woman and can't be taken for granted.
人生无常 我也是
Life's a bitch now so am I.
你是谁?
Who are you?
蝙蝠背后是什么人?
Who's the man behind the bat?
也许你能帮我找出
Maybe you can help me find
在猫背后的
the woman
女人
behind the cat.
不 那不是你
No that's not you.
这才是你
There you are.
被猫担架救了一条命
Saved by Kitty Litter.
混蛋!
Bastard!
阿佛瑞德
Alfred
帮我拿消毒软膏来 好吗?
bring me some antiseptic ointment.
来了 会痛吗 主人?
Coming. Are you in pain sir?
不太会
Not really.
我或许救了市长的宝宝
I may have saved the mayor's baby
但我拒绝救如婴儿般
but I refuse to save a mayor
束手无策的市长
who stood by helpless as a baby
使高谭市遭到破坏
while Gotham was ravaged by a disease
使老鹰童子军变成疯狂小丑
that turned Eagle Scouts into crazed clowns
快乐的主妇变成猫女
and happy homemakers into catwomen.
谢谢
Thank you.
奥兹瓦.卡伯波特... 神秘的人兽企图经营高谭市
Oswald Cobblepot the mystery man-beast made his bid to run Gotham.
卡伯波特先生 你是年轻人的最佳模范
Mr. Cobblepot you are the coolest role model a young person could have.
妳是模范能得到的
And you're the hottest young person
最热情的年轻人
a role model could have.
来
Here.
戴个徽章
Wear a button.
让我帮妳戴在这里
Let me just get it on here.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
我真的会喜欢候选市长这种事 非关权力 而是接触人民
This mayor stuff is not about power it's about reaching out to people
触摸人民 抚摸人民
touching people groping people.
- 企鹅... - 我不叫企鹅!
- Penguin... - My name is not Penguin!
我是奥兹瓦.卡伯波特
It's Oswald Cobblepot.
奥兹瓦 有人要见你
Oswald there's somebody here to see you.
正是我在找的女人
Just the pussy I've been looking for.
这里真冷
It's chilly in here.
我会使妳温暖
I'll warm you.
冷静 奥兹瓦
Down Oswald.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
你瞧
You see
你和我有共通之处
you and I have something in common.
听来很熟悉
Sounds familiar.
毁灭的僻好?
Appetite for destruction?
对流行大师的鄙视?
Contempt for the czars of fashion?
等等 别告诉我
Wait don't tell me.
赤裸裸的性魅力?
Naked sexual charisma?
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
我们的共同仇敌
The thorn in both our sides.
药膏中的苍蝇
The fly in our ointment.
药膏?
Ointment?
我有有气味的和无气味的
I've got scented and unscented.
我会再回来
I'll come back later.
对了 妳是登记投票人吗? 我是市长候选人
Perchance are you a registered voter? I'm a mayoral prospect.
我今天来只有一个目的...
I have but one pet cause today!.
打倒蝙蝠
Ban the Bat.
噢 又是他 没问题 他已经完了 妳看
Oh him again. No bother. He's already history. Check it out.
我们要拆开他的蝙蝠车 将它变成活动氢弹
We'll disassemble his Batmobile and turn it into an H-bomb on wheels.
不 不 他的力量比殉道者还大
He'd have even more power as a martyr.
要消灭蝙蝠侠 首先得将他变成他最痛恨的人
To destroy Batman we must first turn him into what he hates the most.
那就是... 我们
Namely us.
妳是指陷害他?
Frame him?
还没上任就有黑名单了
Not even in office yet and already an enemies list.
那些名字不能任人窥探
Those names are not for prying eyes.
我为何要信任一个猫女?
Why should I trust some catbroad anyway?
也许妳只是个心理不平衡的名媛 想报复父亲
Maybe you're a screwed-up sorority chick getting back at her daddy
只因她年满16岁时 没帮她买匹小马
for not buying her that pony when she turned sweet-sixteen.
好鸟
Nice birdie.
好猫
Nice kitty.
好猫　好猫
蝙蝠侠伤了我的手臂
Batman napaimed my arm.
在我才开始满意自己时 就害我跌落谷底
He knocked me off a buiiding just when I started to feel good about myself.
我要在他坠落时 扮演重要角色
I want to play an integral part in his degradation.
计划正在形成
A pian is forming.
我要参加
I want in.
想到要害蝙蝠侠 就令我觉得
The thought of busting Batman makes me feei all
肮脏
dirty.
或许我就在这儿 给自己洗个澡
Maybe I'll just give myseif a bath right here.
我质疑市长
I challenge the mayor
明晚在高谭广场要重新点燃圣诞树
to re-light the Christmas tree in Gotham Plaza tomorrow night.
主人 我们该不该换个频道 看些高级节目呢?
Sir shaii we change the channei to a program with some dignity and ciass?
爱的联机怎么样?
The Love Connection perhaps?
不是我对市长没信心
not that I have any faith in the mayor.
但我希望和祈祷
But I hope and pray
蝙蝠侠
that Batman
能在场并维护和平
will be present to preserve the peace.
不可思议
Subtle.
为何你要这样做?
Why are you doing this?
瑟琳娜?
Selina?
抱歉 我不是想吓妳
Sorry I didn't mean to scare you.
吓我?我是自己吓到而已
Scare me? I was just scaring myself.
我不知道为何 但
I don't see how but .
很高兴在远离许瑞克的真实世界中见到妳
it's nice to see you in the real world away from Shreck.
很高兴是在这里
it's nice to be here.
妳没事吧?
Are you all right?
妳看起来有点忧郁或者有心事
You look like you have the holiday blues or something.
帅哥 这几天的新闻
Boy the news these days.
怪怪的!
Weird!
我听电视上说"猫女重140磅"
I heard on TV that Catwoman weighs 140 pounds.
这些人晚上睡饱了没事干?
How do these hacks sleep at night?
那还更扯 居然说"蝙蝠侠炸的"?
it's not even accurate. "Batman blows it"?
他很可能独自救了百万人的生命财产
He probabiy saved miliions in property damage alone.
你不是要去参加重燃圣诞树典礼吗?
You're not going to the re-lighting of the tree are you?
我才不要自找没趣
I wouldn't be caught dead there.
那可是今晚这寒冷城镇最热闹的时刻
it's going to be a hot time in the cold town tonight.
妳属于黑暗一类的 不是吗?
You got kind of a dark side don't you?
没有比你更黑暗的了
No darker than yours.
妳何不来我那儿 一起在电视前看?
Why don't you come over and we can watch it on TV?
圣诞树点亮典礼
The tree-lighting ceremony.
不行 我今晚还有别处要去
I can't. I have to be somewhere tonight.
下午五点来我家晚餐 如何?
How about coming for dinner at five?
或者六点如何?
Let's say six?
好的 五点
Five.
就五点 妳和我
Five. You and me.
圣诞树一亮 然后我按钮
The tree lights up and then I push the button.
等等 等等
Wait wait.
我按钮 然后圣诞树就亮了
I push the button then the tree lights up.
你是谁?
Who are you?
星探
Talent scout.
请进
Come in.
你知道我不但会点亮圣诞树 我还是个女演员
I don't just iight trees. I'm an actress as well.
那是什么东西? 照像机还是什么?
What is that thing? A camera or something?
这叫"好东西!"
Say "Cheese! "
好东西
Cheese.
谢谢你 阿佛瑞德
Thanks Aifred.
我确信他是个好同伴
I'm sure he's wonderfui company
但"富有单身汉"不觉得无聊吗?
but doesn't the "gold-plated-bacheior" bit get a little stale?
我猜和"寂寞秘书"一样
A lot like the "lonely-secretary" syndrome I guess.
执行助理
Executive Assistant.
抱歉
Sorry.
秘书
Secretary.
有女朋友吗?
Any girlfriend?
当然
Sure.
噢 你是说 认真的?
You mean as in serious?
不 有过一个 没再交往了
No. Had one didn't work.
出了什么差错? 慢着!
What went wrong? Hang on!
我想我知道!
I think I know!
你有事瞒着她
You kept things from her.
不 我将一切都告诉她
I told her everything.
而那个事实吓到了她?
The truth frightened her?
有两个事实
There are two truths
妳知道吗?
you know?
她无法调和二者 因为我也无法
She had troubie reconciiing them because I had trouble
调和二者 是
reconciiing them.
所以 维基认为...
Vicki thought...
维基?
Vicki?
溜冰好手或空姐?
ice skater or stewardess?
不 她是个摄影记者
No she was a photojournalist.
那对你双重性的困扰
Was Vicki right about your
维基的看法对吗?
difficulty with duality?
妳知道的
You see
我若说是 那
if I say yes then
妳会以为我是个
you'll think of me as a
像泰德.邦迪的杀人狂 而且
Norman Bates a Ted Bundy type and .
也许不肯让我吻妳
You might not let me kiss you.
会令人失望的 一向是所谓的正常人
it's the so-called normai guys who always let you down.
狂人从未吓到我 至少他们执着
Sickos never scare me. At ieast they're committed.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
我也不能
Neither can i.
这是特别报导 冰雪公主被绑架了
This is a special bulletin. The Ice Princess has been kidnapped.
戈登署长 你能证实 蝙蝠侠涉嫌绑架的传闻吗?
Can you confirm reports of Batman's suspected involvement in the abduction?
这个证据纯粹是间接的
The evidence is purely circumstantial.
它沾了血迹 是在失踪女孩的更衣室找到的
This was found stained with blood in the missing girl's dressing room.
- 我得走了 - 不 是我 这是你家
- I must go. - No it's your house.
慢着 坐一下 轻松点 我马上回来
Hoid on. Just sit for a second and reiax. I'll be right back.
阿佛瑞德 我得到广场去 我看到了
I've got to go to the piaza.
- 是 我知道 他正乞求我出现 - 我希望你别理他 好吗?
- He is begging me to show. - I hoped you'd snub him.
不行 那是绑架案 听着 我要你这么做
I can't. There's been a kidnapping. Here's what I want you to do.
糟糕!
Shit!
告诉瑟琳娜 也就是凯尔小姐 告诉她 我得进城去
Teii Selina Ms. Kyie I had to go out of town.
告诉她 我突然有笔大生意要处理 不 你知道吧?告诉她
Tell her that a big business deal came up . You know what?
让她知道 不是用愚蠢的"做我女友"的方法...
Let her know not in some kind of dumb "be-my-girlfriend" way...
我会转达讯息的 太好了
I'll relay the message.
凯尔小姐　阿佛瑞德 韦恩先生叫我告诉妳...
Mr. Wayne toid me to tell you that...
韦恩先生? 布鲁斯 对
Bruce yes .
可否代我告诉他
Wouid you tell him
我历经许多 改变 .
I've been going through a lot of changes and .
不 只要告诉他
Just that
我的突然离去
this is not a rejection
并非拒绝
my abruptly leaving.
事实上 他使我觉得有
In fact he makes me feel the way.
我真正希望拥有的感受
I hope I really am.
不!你能编个借口或是 找个理由吗?
Couid you just make up a sonnet or a dirty limerick?
我正好想到一个
One has just sprung to mind.
谢谢 这边 小姐　抱歉
This way ma'am.
女士 先生们
Ladies and Gentlemen.
女士 先生们 请注意一下好吗?
Please may I have your attention?
我知道对许多人而言
I know that to many of you
近来高谭市似乎灾祸不断
Gotham seems a bit beleaguered these days.
但我要你们知道 你们选的官员
But I want you to know your elected officials
和警方
and your police department
已经控制住情势
have the situation well in hand.
要快点
Got to hurry.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是陷阱 好让人觉得是我做的
it was set up to look like I did it.
别担心 我会告诉警方 我是被一个有鱼腥味的丑鸟人所绑架
I'll tell the police I was kidnapped by an ugly birdman with fish breath.
有人提到鱼吗?
Did somebody say fish?
我整天都未进食!
I haven't been fed all day.
吃地板吧
Eat floor.
高纤
High fiber.
嘿 帅哥
Hey stud
- 我以为我们互相吸引 - 没错
- I thought we had something together. - We do.
得走了 女孩说的
Got to go. Girl talk.
她放我走了 我想是因为我以女孩立场跟她讲理
She let me go. I think 'cause I reasoned with her girl-to-girl.
小心 别动
Be carefui. Don't move.
草地飞镖!
Lawn dart!
有翅膀的老鼠 做拿手的事吧
Rats with wings do your thing.
蝙蝠侠推落冰雪公主!
Batman pushed the Princess!
停火!
Hoid your fire!
你对我这种女孩 很有吸引力
You're catnip to a girl like me.
英俊 迷人
Handsome dazed
值得付出一切代价
and to die for.
妳若吃檞寄生会致命
Mistietoe can be deadly if you eat it.
但你若认真
But a kiss
一个吻会更致命
can be even deadlier if you mean it.
你是这礼拜第二个杀我的人
You're the second man who's killed me this week.
但我还剩七条命
But I've got seven lives ieft.
我试过救妳...
I tried to save you...
似乎你企图救的女人 结果都死了
Seems like every woman you try to save ends up dead.
或大为责怪你
Or deepiy resentfui.
也许你该退休了
Maybe you shouid retire.
可恶
Damn.
真出色!
Outstanding!
妳是美女与野兽
You're Beauty and the Beast
以性感包装的圣诞礼物
in one iuscious Christmas gift pack.
你说你只要吓吓冰雪公主
You said you'd scare the ice Princess.
她看来蛮怕我的
She iooked pretty scared to me.
来点香槟?
A touch of the bubbiy?
那么 我们还在等什么?
So what are we waiting for?
让我们结合圆房吧
Let's consummate our fiendish union.
你在说些什么?
What?
噢 别这样
Oh come on.
妳无法想象吗?
Can't you picture?
市长的华宅一片黑暗
it's dark in the mayor's mansion.
我精疲力尽 于是妳进卧室
I'm bushed so here you come into the bedroom
扭着妳的小尾巴
twitching your littie tail
一手拿我的拖鞋 一手拿杯纯马丁尼
my slippers in one hand a dry martini in the other.
多棒啊
Piease.
我无论如何都不会碰你
I wouldn't touch you to scratch you.
妳这差劲的妞儿!我该阉掉妳的! 少在那儿装模作样!
You lousy minx! I should have you spayed! You sent out all the signals!
我想我不再喜欢妳了!
I don't think like you anymore!
再见 我无缘的人
Good-bye my unintended.
上天堂吧
Go to heaven.
他在那里!
There he is!
别调整屏幕
Don't adjust your sets.
欢迎光临
Welcome
奥兹瓦.卡伯波特驾驶学校
to the Oswald Cobblepot School of Driving.
各位先生 开始尖叫吧
Gentlemen start your screaming.
也许此时提起 时机不对 但我的驾照过期了!
This may be a bad time to mention it but my license has expired!
轻松点
Relax.
我会对付高谭市那些 尖叫的 可怜的白痴市民!
I'll take care of the squealing wretched pinhead puppets of Gotham!
你必须承认 我玩弄这个臭城市于股掌之间!
You must admit I played this stinking city like a harp from hell!
十二点方向 有个无助的老太太!
Helpless old lady at 12:00 high!
真有趣
That's funny.
现在我有点担心了
Now I'm a iittie worried.
就算他活着 有什么好担心?
So he survived. Why worry?
他毫发无伤! 眼珠子!失禁!都没有!
He didn't even iose a iimb! An eyeball! Biadder control!
重点是听听他们 他们对旧象征已失去信心
Listen to them. They've iost faith in oid symbois.
他们已认同你是未来的代表
They're ready to bond with you the icon of the future.
若是成功 就别再改变
if it works don't fix it.
我们今晚在我的周年舞会上庆祝
We'll ceiebrate tonight at my annual ball.
许瑞克和卡伯波特
Shreck and Cobbiepot
耀眼的联盟 走吧
the visionary alliance.
在维护我们这个
When it came time
美丽城市的时刻
to ensure the safety of our fair city
市长有计划吗?
did the mayor have a plan?
没有!
No!
他依赖一个人
He relied on a man.
一个蝙蝠侠
A Batman.
一个服装怪异的定时炸弹 .
A ticking time-bomb of a costumed freak .
我们主要关切的是这个可怕的怪物
Our prime concern is this ghastiy grotesque.
但也别忘了修蝙蝠车
But let's not forget about repairing the Batmobiie.
得考虑安全问题
There's security to consider.
我们不能将它任意送到一个修车厂
We can't just take it to any oid body shop.
安全问题?
Security?
谁让维基.维尔进蝙蝠洞?
Who let Vicki Vaie into the Batcave?
我正在工作 一转身 她便在那里:"嗨 维基 请进"
I'm working I turn around and there she is. "Hi Vick. Come on in."
- 准备好了吗? - 我想我走楼梯
- Ready? - I'll take the stairs.
你们问我 我是否为个人荣耀上场?
You ask am I up here for personal glory?
不是
No.
我渴望重拾的荣耀
The glory that I yearn to recapture
是高谭市的荣耀!
is the glory of Gotham!
我要如何达成?
How can this be accomplished?
我知道
I know
你们都很关心
you're all concerned.
轻松点
Relax.
我会对付高谭市那些 尖叫的 可怜的白痴市民
I'll take care of the squealing wretched pinhead puppets of Gotham.
我没有那么说
I didn't say that.
你必须承认 我玩弄这个臭城市
You must admit I played this stinking city
于股掌之间! 嘿
like a harp from hell!
你必须承认
You must admit
我玩弄这个臭城市于股掌之间! 嘿
I played this stinking city like a harp from hell!
为什么总有人带着蛋和蕃茄参加演说?
Why is there aiways someone who brings eggs and tomatoes to a speech?
他在那里!
There he is!
我的宝贝们
My babies.
你们想我吗?
Did you miss me?
很棒的演说 奥兹瓦
Great speech Oswaid.
我不叫奥兹瓦!
My name is not Oswaid!
是企鹅!
it's Penguin!
我不是人类!
I am not a human being!
我是个冷血动物!
I am an animal. Cold-blooded!
空调加强点!
Crank the A.C.!
我的名单呢?将名字送上来!
Where are my lists? Bring me the names!
时候到了
it's time.
这些是高谭市长子们的名字
These are the names of the first-born sons of Gotham City.
就和我一样
Just like I was.
而和我一样 可怕的命运在等着他们
And like me a terribie fate waits for them.
今晚 当他们的父母狂欢时
Tonight while their parents party
他们将作梦
they'll be dreaming away
在他们的摇篮
in their safe cribs
在他们的软床
their soft beds
而我们将劫走他们
and we'll snatch them
带他们到下水道
carry them into the sewer
将他们丢进深黑的水底坟墓
and toss them into a deep dark watery grave.
企鹅?
Penguin?
杀死熟睡儿童
Kiiiing sieeping children
岂不是有一点
isn't that a littie .
不 是很多
No it's a lot.
韦恩先生 提醒你
A reminder.
今晚那个可恶的许瑞克先生 要举办讨厌的派对
Tonight is that ioathsome party hosted by the odious Mr. Shreck.
我们能严正回绝吗?
May we RSVP in the resoundingiy negative?
没兴趣
Not interested.
不过
Although
瑟琳娜.凯尔可能会在场
Selina Kyie might be there.
真出色的服装
ingenious costume.
我来猜猜看
Let me guess.
基金会的好人?
Trust-fund goody-goody?
感觉很好吧?
Feeiing good?
你差点使一个怪物当上高谭市长
You almost made a monster the mayor of Gotham City.
我是本市之光
I am the light of this city
我是它卑劣 疯狂的灵魂
and I am its mean twisted soul.
谁当市长有关系吗?
Does it matter who's mayor?
对我而言是的
it does to me.
无聊
Yawn.
听着 昨天很抱歉 我得
I'm sorry about yesterday but I had
去处理一大笔生意
a pretty big deal come through. Fall through actually.
没关系 我得回家去喂我的猫
it's okay. I had to go home and feed my cat.
那不伤感情啰?
No hard feelings then?
事实上
Actuaiiy
应该是半伤
semi-hard I'd say.
寝具部有个大而舒适的双人床
There's a big comfy California King over in Bedding.
我们何不 .
Why don't we .
脱掉舞会服装吗?
Take off our costumes?
我已厌倦戴面具了
I'm tired of wearing masks.
我也是
Me too.
让我问妳一件事
Let me ask you something.
妳今晚为何而来?
Why'd you come tonight?
- 你先说 - 来看妳
- You first. - To see you.
说得真好
Lovely.
但愿我能说同样的话 但我是为了麦斯来的
I wish I couid say the same but I came for Max.
妳的意思是妳 .
Do you mean you .
该不会妳和麦斯?
Not you and Max?
哈 我和麦斯?
Me and Max?
不 这个和麦斯
No. This and Max.
不 别告诉我杀死麦斯无法解决一切 因为那一定会的
Don't tell me killing Max won't solve anything because it will.
你不厌倦这虚伪的强盗大亨
Aren't you tired of this sanctimonious robber baron
总是获胜 他不该被埋在六呎以下吗?
coming out on top when he should be six feet under?
妳或许和妳老板之间有很多问题 但妳以为妳是谁啊?
You may have problems with your boss but who do you think you are?
我已经不知道了 布鲁斯
I don't know anymore Bruce.
檞寄生下的吻
A kiss under the mistietoe.
"妳若吃檞寄生会致命"
"Mistietoe can be deadly if you eat it."
但你若认真
But a kiss can be even deadlier
一个吻会更致命
if you mean it.
噢 我的天
Oh my God.
这是否意味我们得开始打斗?
Does this mean we have to start fighting?
我们到外面去
Let's go outside.
- 爸　儿子 你没事吧?　- 我很好
- Are you okay? - I'm all right.
你们没邀请我
You didn't invite me
所以我不请自来!
so I crashed!
你要做什么?
What do you want?
现在 我的部队
Right now my troops
正在全城搜寻
are fanning out across town
你们的孩子!
for your children!
没错!
Yes!
是你们的长子!
For your first-born sons!
你们使他无助在家
The ones you left defenseless at home
好让自己能打扮得像傻瓜
so you could dress up like jerks
喝着果汁和跳舞
get juiced and dance
坏透了!
badly!
我亲自前来
I've personally come
为抓高谭市最喜爱的儿子
for Gotham's favorite son
奇普.许瑞克先生
Mr. Chip Shreck.
跟我走 你这个大白痴
You're coming with me you Great White Dope
以便死在下面的下水道中!
to die way down in the sewer!
别抓奇普 你若有丝毫人 就抓我代替吧
Not Chip. if you have any human feeiing take me instead.
我没有 因此 不行!
I don't. So no!
我才是你要的
I'm the one you want.
操纵和背叛你的 不是麦斯.许克吗?
Isn't it Max Shreck who manipuiated and betrayed you?
不就是麦斯 而非奇普
Isn't it Max not Chip
你要看到他在下水道中淹死的?
you want to see immersed to his eyeballs in raw sewage?
好吧 你说的有理
Okay you got a point.
我就暂时让这小子活着
I'll let the littie prince live for now.
进鸭子里去!
in the duck!
实在太好了
This is going to be good
在高谭市最有希望的作物成熟前
to cut down a whoie crop of Gotham's most promising
将它们砍断
before their prime.
你是在问我 如何引诱他们?
You ask me how do I lure them in?
一点"杂耍企鹅"把戏
A littie "Pied Penguin" action.
你可以看着他们沈入
And you get to watch them sink
一大池
into a deep puddle
你的工业副产品中
of your industrial by-products.
然后
Then
你再加入他们
you join them.
快点将那些孩子装好 好吗?
Hurry up and get those kids loaded.
这边走 孩子们
Right this way kiddies.
跟我走
Come with me.
所有小孩在哪呢?
So where are all the children?
"亲爱的企鹅:"
"Dear Penguin:
"小孩们懊悔不克参加"
"The chiidren regret they're unabie to attend.
"蝙蝠侠!"
"Batman! "
我亲爱的企鹅们
My dear penguins
我们站在一个大关键点上!
we stand on a great threshold!
害怕是正常的!
it's okay to be scared!
你们有许多人将回不来
Many of you won't be coming back.
多谢蝙蝠侠
Thanks to Batman
惩罚所有神的子民的时刻
the time has come
来临了!
to punish all God's chiidren!
长子 次子 三子和四子!
First-second-third-and fourth-born!
为何要有偏见?
Why be biased?
男的和女的!
Male and female!
妈的 男女平等
Hell the sexes are equal
将他们的性感带
with their erogenous zones
炸向高空!
blown sky-high!
向前走
Forward
前进!
march!
解放高谭市
The liberation of Gotham
已经开始!
has begun!
企鹅们在地面上活动了
The penguins are moving above ground.
企鹅部队
Penguin army
接近发射目的地... 高谭广场
approaching launch destination at Gotham Plaza.
距发射一分钟
One minute until ignition.
他们不尊重我
They wouldn't put me on a pedestal
我就让他们送命!
so I'm laying them on a slab!
企鹅似乎在高谭广场集结
Penguins seem to be converging on Gotham Plaza.
距发射三十秒
Thirty seconds until ignition.
发射后估计死亡人数:
Estimated casualties after launch:
十万人
100,000 people.
企鹅们已抵达高谭广场
The penguins have reached Gotham Square.
距发射十五秒
Fifteen seconds to ignition.
准备好了 主人
Ready when you are sir.
10 9 8 7
10-9-8-7
好了 让他们转向 是 主人
Let's turn them around.
情况不对
Something is wrong.
讯号被干扰了
Something has jammed the signal.
他们似乎转向了
They seem to be turning around.
过来 还有某种东西往这边来了
There is also something coming this way.
非常大 非常快
Very large. Very fast.
谁在那里?
Who's there?
我进入讯号中心了
I'm homing in on the signal's origin.
你嫉妒我是个纯种怪物
You're jealous because I'm a genuine freak
而你得戴着面具!
and you have to wear a mask!
也许你说得对
You might be right.
但最重要的是: 谁拿着雨伞?
But what it all comes down to is: Who's holding the umbrella?
我的宝贝啊!
My babies!
我不知道妳想要什么 但只要我花一点功夫 就能弄到
I don't know what you want but I can get it with a minimum of fuss.
金钱
Money.
珠宝
Jewels.
很大一串的珠宝
A very big ball of string.
你的血 麦斯 我的血?
Your blood Max.
我在办公室捐过了
I gave at the office.
只有半品脱 我要的是半加仑
A half-pint. I'm taiking gallons.
我们来谈条件!
Let's make a deal!
除了我的血 我能为妳做什么?
Other than my blood what can I do?
抱歉 麦斯 以死还死
Sorry Max. A die for a die.
你不只在救一条命...
You're not just saving a life...
也是在救 闭嘴 你要去坐牢了
Shut up. You're going to jail.
别天真了 法律对像他这样的人 或我们 都莫可奈何
Don't be naive. The law doesn't apply to people like him or us.
二者皆非
Wrong on both counts.
为何要如此做?
Why do this?
我们将他交给警方
Let's just take him to the police.
然后我们可以
Then we can go home
一起回家
together.
瑟琳娜
Selina
妳不懂吗?
don't you see?
我们是一样的
We're the same.
由中间
Split
分裂为二
down the center.
瑟琳娜 拜托
Piease.
布鲁斯
Bruce
我愿意和你住在你的城堡中
I would love to live with you in your castle
直到永远 一如童话故事
forever just like in a falry tale.
我就是无法忍受我自己 别假装这是个快乐结局
I just couldn't live with myself. Don't pretend this is a happy ending.
瑟琳娜 瑟琳娜.凯尔
Selina Kyie.
妳被开除了
You're fired.
还有布鲁斯.韦恩
And Bruce Wayne
你为何作蝙蝠侠的装扮?
why are you dressed up like Batman?
因为他是蝙蝠侠 低能的家伙!
Because he is Batman you moron!
以前是
Was.
不要
Don't.
你杀我 企鹅杀我 蝙蝠侠杀我
You killed me the Penguin killed me Batman killed me.
去掉三条命 你有足够的子弹解决我吗?
Three lives down. Got enough to finish me off?
只有一个办法能知道
One way to find out.
四
Four.
五
Five.
仍然活着!
Still aiive!
六
Six.
七
Seven.
好女孩都上天堂
All good giris go to heaven.
还剩两条命
Two lives left.
我想该留下一条 过明年的圣诞节
I'll save one for next Christmas.
但在这同时
But in the meantime
吻一下 如何 圣诞老人?
how about a kiss Santie Ciaus?
可恶!
Shit!
选到一把可爱的
I picked a cute one.
热气使我不舒服
The heat's getting to me.
我马上就误杀你
I'll murder you momentariiy.
但首先
But first
我需要喝
I need a cooi drink
冰水
of ice water.
停车
Stop the car.
无论如何
Come what may
圣诞快乐 韦恩先生
Merry Christmas Mr. Wayne.
圣诞快乐 阿佛瑞德
Merry Christmas Aifred.
平安归于男人
Goodwiii toward men.
和女人
And women.